unisuper.com.au 2018-03-13

# 

       Privacy policy
Approved by the Boards of UniSuper Limited and UniSuper Management Pty Limited on 22 June 2017.
Introduction to UniSuper’s Privacy Policy                                                      What is Personal Information?
UniSuper is committed to protecting the privacy and the                                        Personal information is your information and includes
confidentiality of your information. As a superannuation                                       personal details or opinions you may have, for example, your
fund and not for profit organisation, our purpose is to act in                                 name, address, phone number, tax file number, email address,
members’ best interests. We are committed to managing the                                      employment details (including salary) and date of birth.
privacy of all of your information in a secure environment.
                                                                                               If you do not provide us with your personal information, we
This Privacy Policy applies to UniSuper Limited, trustee                                       may not be able to administer your account appropriately, or
and UniSuper Management Pty Ltd1 , the administrator and                                       provide you with a product or service.
explains the way we manage and protect your information.
These related entities share your information and work                                         We may also collect details of your beneficiaries, spouses and
together to provide your membership benefits.                                                  other family members, where you nominate a beneficiary or in
                                                                                               relation to a claim.
                                                                                               At times, Proof of Identification information is necessary
How is Privacy Managed?                                                                        to satisfy regulatory requirements and support our internal
                                                                                               verification procedures. These established industry practices
UniSuper is bound by the Privacy Act 1988 (Privacy Act)                                        ensure we only deal with you when discussing and sharing
which includes 13 Australian Privacy Principles. These                                         information to provide trust and confidence that your
principles regulate the way we handle your personal and                                        information is managed securely.
sensitive information.
We have a sound privacy framework supported by industry                                        How is Personal Information Collected?
practices that comply with our legislative privacy obligations
to ensure you can have confidence that your information
is safe and secure. The framework provides mechanisms                                          UniSuper collects information directly from you at the time
for you to have awareness over the manner in which your                                        your become a member via the application form, over the
information is managed and allows you to:                                                      phone or via our website. UniSuper also collects personal
         understand why your personal information is being                                     information through your employer when you first join
AA                                                                                             UniSuper and while you are a member of the fund. This
         collected, how it will be used and who it will be disclosed to
         access a copy of your personal information                                            information may include your name, address, TFN, contact
AA                                                                                             details and employment details.
AA       “opt-out” of unwanted direct marketing material
AA       correct inaccurate personal information, and
AA       make a complaint regarding the handling of your
         personal information.
We are committed to complying with our privacy law
obligations and managing them openly and transparently
with you.
1	UniSuper Limited ABN 54 006 027 121 (USL) is the trustee of the UniSuper superannuation fund ABN 91 385 943 850 (the Fund). UniSuper Management Pty Ltd
    ABN 91 006 961 799, Australian Financial Services Licence No. 235907 (USM) has been appointed by USL to administer the Fund. USM is also licensed to provide
    financial services to members, such as financial advice and related services. In this Policy, USL, USM and the Fund are referred to collectively as UniSuper.
unisuper.com.au

Why does UniSuper collect                                     Other Types of Information
Personal Information?                                         UniSuper collects
UniSuper only collects information from you if is necessary   SENSITIVE INFORMATION
to carry out our functions and activities. This is so we can
                                                              Sensitive information is a subset of personal information,
establish your account, administer your account(s), ensure
                                                              which is afforded a higher level of privacy protection. Sensitive
you are eligible for insurance cover, provide you with the
                                                              information includes information about your health, race or
benefits of membership, verify your identity and improve
                                                              ethnicity, political opinions, criminal records, religious beliefs
member services (e.g. through research, marketing, product
                                                              or affiliations, trade union or professional memberships.
development and planning). We will also collect personal
information from you if you choose to receive financial       UniSuper’s policy is only to collect sensitive information
advice and related services from us.                          where it is reasonably necessary for us to perform our
                                                              services and either:
UniSuper collects and holds your Tax File Number (TFN) for
                                                              AA   you have consented; or
approved purposes under superannuation and taxation law.
                                                              AA   we are required or authorised by or under law to do so.
                                                              We will only obtain sensitive information from you if we
How we use your Personal                                      need this information. If you do not provide this information,
Information that we collect                                   we may not be able to administer your account effectively,
                                                              provide you with a product or service.
UniSuper uses and discloses your personal information for     HEALTH INFORMATION
the purposes for which we have collected your information,    When we collect and manage health information, we comply
as set out above.                                             with the terms of our Privacy Policy and relevant law and in
UniSuper may also use your personal information to            accordance with the following principles:
undertake activities for a purpose related to the above.      AA   UniSuper will collect health information only with your
                                                                   consent or where it is required or authorised by law.
                                                              AA   Generally, UniSuper will collect health information
What happens if UniSuper is unable                                 from you directly. However, in some cases, UniSuper
                                                                   may collect health information about you from others,
to collect Personal Information?                                   such as your treating doctor. This will be done only with
                                                                   your consent.
If UniSuper is unable to collect certain personal information AA   UniSuper may use and/or disclose your health
from you, we may not be able to administer your account,           information but will do so only with your consent or for
deliver our services, provide products and provide your            the primary purpose for which it was collected (that is,
benefits to you or to your beneficiaries. Also, if we are          to enable the insurer or UniSuper to determine whether
unable to collect certain personal information from you,           to offer you additional insurance or to enable UniSuper
we may not be able to administer your benefits at all or you       and/or the insurer to assess your claim for payment of a
may be disadvantaged in some other way. For example, if            relevant benefit)
you fail to provide your tax file number, UniSuper will not   AA   It will not always be possible for UniSuper to give you
able to accept any voluntary after-tax (non-concessional)          the opportunity to correct health information held about
contributions from you and additional tax may be deducted          you. However, even where UniSuper cannot correct
from any employer or salary sacrifice (concessional)               health information as requested, UniSuper will take all
contributions made by you or your employer.                        reasonable steps to note any statement you make about
                                                                   the relevant health information.
In other cases, if we are unable to collect certain personal
information (e.g. your email address), we will not be able to GOVERNMENT IDENTIFIERS
provide you with member communications or other services      UniSuper is authorised by law to collect government
as quickly or as effectively as we otherwise might.           related identifiers such as your TFN. UniSuper will not use
                                                              or disclose this information other than when required or
                                                              authorised by law.
unisuper.com.au

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION WHEN MAKING A CLAIM                                               Disclosure of your Personal Information
UniSuper may require additional information when
you make a claim for a benefit (for example, a total and
permanent disablement benefit). We use this information to
                                                                                         DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
ensure that you are entitled to benefits and can better assess                           TO THIRD PARTIES
your claim. Under these circumstances, we will explain the                               UniSuper engages certain external organisations to assist in the
reasons we require the information and provide you with                                  provision of services to you (e.g. mail-houses, auditors, insurers,
further information regarding the purposes for which the                                 actuaries, lawyers and research consultants). UniSuper discloses
information is required.                                                                 your personal information to such organisations but does so only
                                                                                         for the purpose of providing, administering or improving your
                                                                                         superannuation membership, benefits or services.
How does UniSuper hold and store
                                                                                         In these instances UniSuper will engage third parties on
your Personal Information?                                                               contractual terms and ensure that they hold, use and disclose
                                                                                         your personal information in accordance with the Privacy Act.
UniSuper takes all necessary precautions to ensure your
                                                                                         UniSuper also engages with your employer and may disclose
personal information (in both physical and electronic form)
                                                                                         your personal information to your employer in order to verify
is secure. In particular, UniSuper operates in a secure
                                                                                         your contributions and employment details, provide you with
environment that ensures protection of all paper-based
                                                                                         benefits and administer your superannuation benefits.
personal information. As part of their roles, UniSuper
staff are required to respect the privacy of all personal                                Where required under relevant law, UniSuper will disclose
information in their possession. Further, all UniSuper                                   your personal information to government agencies (such
information technology systems employ data security                                      as the Australian Taxation Office) and a regulator such
software and hardware.                                                                   as the Australian Prudential Regulation Authority or the
                                                                                         Australian Securities and Investments Commission.
Any personal information held by UniSuper will be
destroyed or permanently de-identified when it is no                                     OVERSEAS DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
longer needed for any purpose for which UniSuper
might legitimately use or disclose it. We typically retain                               In order to provide our services and products to you, we may,
information as required by our regulatory obligations and                                in some circumstances, transfer or disclose your personal
company requirements.                                                                    information to overseas entities. The countries to which
                                                                                         your personal information may be transferred are currently
In accordance with our policy, no personal information                                   Japan, Canada and USA 2 and additional countries may be
is destroyed or de-identified if it relates to an existing or                            added to this list in future.
anticipated legal proceedings.
                                                                                         Where information is transferred overseas, we will seek
                                                                                         to ensure the recipient of the data has security systems to
Dealing with us Anonymously                                                              prevent misuse, loss or unauthorised disclosure in line with
                                                                                         Australian laws and standards.
or with a Pseudonym
You can deal with UniSuper anonymously or with a                                         Direct Marketing
pseudonym where it is lawful and practicable to do so. A
pseudonym is a name or other description that is different                               UniSuper considers acting in your best interests as being integral
from your own name.                                                                      to our business operations. UniSuper offers two main types of
                                                                                         communication: member education, where we communicate to
In these circumstances, as we are limited in the amount of
                                                                                         you about the benefits of your UniSuper membership, and direct
information that we have about you, we may be limited in
                                                                                         marketing, where we promote our services to you.
our ability to provide our services and products applicable to
your particular circumstances.                                                           If you do not wish to be contacted about our new products
                                                                                         or services, you may opt-out of direct marketing at any time.
If you would like to receive complete and accurate
                                                                                         For e-mail communications, you can opt-out of receiving
information from UniSuper, you will need to provide us with
                                                                                         e-mails by selecting the “unsubscribe” option, which is
your personal details so that we can verify your identity and
                                                                                         attached at the base of the e-mail.
provide you with appropriate products.
                                                                                         If you do not want to receive letters relating to direct marketing
                                                                                         communication, please notify us. Please see details at the end of
                                                                                         this policy for information about how to contact us.
2
  The Privacy Act requires that we disclose the countries that we may disclose personal information to.
unisuper.com.au

Electronic Information,                                         SECURITY AND STORAGE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
                                                                We are committed to protecting the personal information
Privacy and the Internet                                        we hold about you. UniSuper takes all reasonable steps
                                                                to protect your personal information, including the use
We use the internet, computers and e-mail as an integral part   of encryption technology. We take all reasonable steps to
of our business to provide services to you. We administer a     ensure your information is secure from loss, interference,
monitoring programme to ensure that our technology is           modification, misuse, unauthorized access and disclosure.
managed appropriately including internet, intranet and network  Our systems are subject to regular audit, and are maintained
traffic. We aim to ensure that all data is free from viruses.   based on appropriate industry guidelines. UniSuper ensures
                                                                that all information is backed up and stored securely in a
We provide a website for the benefit of members to facilitate   remote location. All access to personal information is by
account management (www.unisuper.com.au). Generally,            authorised staff only and is carefully monitored.
any personal information that is collected from and managed
via the website is collected and managed in the same manner
as other personal information. However, there are some          Complaints and Inquiries
additional features of the website that are slightly different.
These are as follows:
                                                                UniSuper has a complaints handling and inquiries team, as
AA   MemberOnline: We allow you to access and
                                                                well as and processes in place to ensure that we deal with
     update personal information for your account on
                                                                complaints and questions from members, employers, and the
     MemberOnline. To log-in, you will be required to
                                                                general public.
     enter a user name and password. Your user name and
     password will protect your personal information from       We appreciate that sometimes inquiries regarding your
     unauthorised access and use. You must not disclose your    personal information may not be resolved to your satisfaction
     user name and password to any other person.                or may need further investigation. If this is the case you can
                                                                make a formal complaint regarding a privacy matter.
     If you click on a link in our website that leads you to
     another organisation’s website, UniSuper will cease to     To make a complaint regarding a privacy matter you can
     be responsible for the privacy or security of any personal write to us at:
     information that you may provide to the operator of
     the linked site. You should check with the linked site’s   Complaints Officer
     operator as to its policies on privacy before providing    UniSuper
     them with your personal information.                       Level 1, 385 Bourke Street
AA   Cookies: We may use technology to track the patterns of    Melbourne VIC 3000
     behaviour of visitors to our site. This can include using
     a “cookie”, which would be stored on your browser. This    When we have received your complaint, we’ll send you a
     is collected for the purpose of improving the usefulness   confirmation letter. We will then attempt to resolve your
     and usability of the site. You can usually modify your     complaint as quickly as we can. If you are not satisfied with
     browser to prevent this from happening.                    the outcome of the complaint, you can refer your privacy
     Verification of identify: Sometimes we may use your        complaint to the Australian Information Commissioner at
AA                                                              www.oaic.gov.au or call them on 1300 363 992.
     personal information you provide to UniSuper in order
     to verify your identity via an online electronic service.
     We will only use your personal information in such a
                                                                DATA BREACH RESPONSE
     way if we have obtained your consent to do so.             We take the security of your personal information very
                                                                seriously and take reasonable steps to protect your personal
                                                                information and secure from loss, misuse, interference and
Technology, Risk and                                            unauthorised access. If an unforseen event were to occur and
our Control Framework                                           UniSuper’s data, including members’ personal information
                                                                was interfered with or accessed by unauthorised persons,
                                                                UniSuper has in place a number of mechanisms to contain
HOW DOES UNISUPER MAINTAIN THE                                  the breach and assess the impact.
QUALITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION?
We take reasonable steps to ensure that our information         If your personal information were to be accessed or
about you is accurate, complete and up-to-date. UniSuper        interfered with by unauthorised persons, we would comply
encourages you to advise us immediately of any changes to       with any applicable legal obligations to notify you.
your personal information, especially if it may affect your
benefits directly (e.g. changes to your name, address or
nominated beneficiaries).
unisuper.com.au

Access and Correction                                                                                                     Amendment to the Privacy Policy
to Personal Information
                                                                                                                          UniSuper may amend this Privacy Policy as required, and we
                                                                                                                          encourage you to check the website for updates.
In order to keep the personal information we hold on record
for you up to date, we ask that you let us know of any changes.
UniSuper will provide you with copies of current personal
                                                                                                                          Contact details
information held about you upon request. Please see the
details at the end of this policy for information about how to                                                            If you require more detailed information on a specific privacy
contact UniSuper.                                                                                                         issue or you have any concerns about UniSuper’s collection,
                                                                                                                          use or disclosure of your personal information, you can:
Sometimes, UniSuper may refuse to provide you with access
to your personal information due to the following reasons                                                                 Write to the:  P            rivacy Officer
(not exhaustive):                                                                                                                                     UniSuper
AA      where it would be unlawful                                                                                                                    Level 1, 385 Bourke Street
AA      may pose a serious and imminent threat to someone’s                                                                                           Melbourne, VIC 3000; or
        health
        the information relates to existing or anticipated legal                                                          E-mail us at enquiry@unisuper.com.au; or
AA
        proceedings
                                                                                                                          Call the UniSuper Helpline on 1800 331 685.
AA      giving access would have an unreasonable impact on the
        privacy of other individuals.                                                                                     For more information about privacy in general, you can visit
                                                                                                                          the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner’s
In some instances UniSuper is unable to release information
                                                                                                                          website www.oaic.gov.au.
provided to it by a third party, for example a medical
practitioner or another health consultant’s report or
information provided by a third party entity. Where this
occurs, UniSuper may refer you to the third party to access
the information directly. In each of these cases, UniSuper
will provide you with reasons for the refusal.
If we are not able to provide you with access, we will notify
you of the reasons for the refusal.
If you believe your personal information is not accurate,
complete, or up-to-date, please contact us (see the Contact
Us section for more information).
This information is of a general nature only and includes general advice. It has been prepared without taking into account your individual objectives, financial situation or needs. Before making any decision in relation to your UniSuper
membership, you should consider your personal circumstances, the relevant product disclosure statement for your membership category and whether to consult a licensed financial adviser.
This information is current as at July 2017 and is based on our understanding of legislation at that date. Information is subject to change. To the extent that this fact sheet contains information which is inconsistent with the
UniSuper Trust Deed and Regulations (together the Trust Deed), the Trust Deed will prevail.
Issued by: UniSuper Management Pty Ltd ABN 91 006 961 799, AFSL No. 235907 on behalf of UniSuper Limited the trustee of UniSuper, Level 1, 385 Bourke Street, Melbourne Vic 3000.
Fund:          UniSuper, ABN 91 385 943 850
Trustee:       UniSuper Limited, ABN 54 006 027 121, AFSL No. 492806
Date:          July 2017
unisuper.com.au
